<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><Esri><MetaID SYNC="true" /><CreaDate SYNC="true" /><CreaTime SYNC="true" /><SyncOnce SYNC="true">TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate SYNC="true" /><ModTime SYNC="true" /></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle sync="true">ESRI Metadata Translator (Conversion)</resTitle><citRespParty><rpIndName /><rpOrgName>ESRI, Inc.</rpOrgName><rpPosName /><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint><city>Redlands</city><adminArea>California</adminArea><postCode>92373 - 8100</postCode><eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd><country>United States</country></cntAddress><cntPhone><voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum><faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum></cntPhone></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd>010</RoleCd></role></citRespParty></idCitation><idAbs>
			<para>Uses the ArcGIS metadata translation engine to export metadata content from ArcGIS to a stand-alone metadata XML file. The exported metadata will be formatted to satisfy the metadata standard associated with the specified translation. </para>
			<para>Metadata for items in ArcGIS is stored in the ArcGIS metadata format. Use the "ESRI-ISO to" translations to export ArcGIS metadata to another metadata XML format. For example, do this  to share information outside of ArcGIS by publishing it to a metadata catalog. Different metadata catalogs accept information in different XML formats. ArcGIS metadata can be exported to different formats  if you must publish your information to metadata catalogs with different requirements.</para>
			<para>When using a "to ISO 19139" translation the exported metadata will be formatted following the rules defined in ISO standard 19139, <italics>Geographic Information—Metadata—Implementation Specification</italics>, and its associated XML Schemas. The translation will also account for the metadata style selected in ArcGIS. For example, when the selected style is <italics>North American Profile of ISO 19115:2003</italics> the output file will be formatted appropriately for that ISO metadata  profile.</para>
			<para>"FGDC" translations handle information in the item's metadata that is formatted according to the Federal Geographic Data Committee's (FGDC)<italics>Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata (CSDGM)</italics>. </para></idAbs><descKeys KeyTypCd="005"><keyTyp><keyTyp>005</keyTyp></keyTyp><keyword>19139</keyword><keyword>Change</keyword><keyword>Convert</keyword><keyword>Export</keyword><keyword>Fgdc</keyword><keyword>Format</keyword><keyword>Import</keyword><keyword>Iso</keyword><keyword>Make</keyword><keyword>Profile</keyword><keyword>Save</keyword><keyword>Standard</keyword><keyword>Style</keyword><keyword>Transfer</keyword><keyword>Translate</keyword><keyword>Turn</keyword><keyword>Xml</keyword></descKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName sync="true">ArcToolBox Tool</formatName></distorFormat><distorTran><onLineSrc><linkage /><protocol /><onFunct><onFunctCd /></onFunct></onLineSrc></distorTran></distributor></distInfo><metainfo><metd Sync="TRUE" /></metainfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE" /><tool name="ESRITranslator" displayname="ESRI Metadata Translator (Conversion)" toolboxalias="conversion" softwarerestriction="none"><summary>
			<para>Uses the ArcGIS metadata translation engine to export metadata content from ArcGIS to a stand-alone metadata XML file. The exported metadata will be formatted to satisfy the metadata standard associated with the specified translation. </para>
			<para>Metadata for items in ArcGIS is stored in the ArcGIS metadata format. Use the "ESRI-ISO to" translations to export ArcGIS metadata to another metadata XML format. For example, do this  to share information outside of ArcGIS by publishing it to a metadata catalog. Different metadata catalogs accept information in different XML formats. ArcGIS metadata can be exported to different formats  if you must publish your information to metadata catalogs with different requirements.</para>
			<para>When using a "to ISO 19139" translation the exported metadata will be formatted following the rules defined in ISO standard 19139, <italics>Geographic Information—Metadata—Implementation Specification</italics>, and its associated XML Schemas. The translation will also account for the metadata style selected in ArcGIS. For example, when the selected style is <italics>North American Profile of ISO 19115:2003</italics> the output file will be formatted appropriately for that ISO metadata  profile.</para>
			<para>"FGDC" translations handle information in the item's metadata that is formatted according to the Federal Geographic Data Committee's (FGDC)<italics>Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata (CSDGM)</italics>. </para></summary><alink_name>ESRITranslator_conversion</alink_name><parameters><param sync="true" name="source" displayname="Source Metadata" datatype="Data Element; Layer" direction="Input" expression="source" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The item whose metadata will be converted, or a stand-alone XML file that will be converted.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The item whose metadata will be converted, or a stand-alone XML file that will be converted.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="translator" displayname="Translation" datatype="File" direction="Input" expression="translator" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>An XML file that defines the conversion that will be performed. </para>
						<para>The translator files provided with ArcGIS Desktop can be found in the &lt;ArcGIS Install Location&gt;\Metadata\Translator folder. The following conversions are supported:</para>
						<bulletList>
							<bullet_item>ArcGIS to ISO 19139 (ESRI_ISO2ISO19139.xml)</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>FGDC to ArcGIS (FGDC2ESRI_ISO.xml)</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>FGDC to ISO 19139 (FGDC2ISO19139.xml)</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>ISO 19139 to ArcGIS (ISO19139_2ESRI_ISO.xml)</bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
						<para>A translator file must be specified. This tool does not have a default value for this parameter.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>An XML file that defines the conversion that will be performed. </para>
						<para>The translator files provided with ArcGIS Desktop can be found in the &lt;ArcGIS Install Location&gt;\Metadata\Translator folder. The following conversions are supported:</para>
						<bulletList>
							<bullet_item>ArcGIS to ISO 19139 (ESRI_ISO2ISO19139.xml)</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>FGDC to ArcGIS (FGDC2ESRI_ISO.xml)</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>FGDC to ISO 19139 (FGDC2ISO19139.xml)</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>ISO 19139 to ArcGIS (ISO19139_2ESRI_ISO.xml)</bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
						<para>A translator file must be specified. This tool does not have a default value for this parameter.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="output" displayname="Output File" datatype="File" direction="Output" expression="output" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>A stand-alone XML file that will be created containing the converted metadata.</para>
						<para>To check for problems in the metadata using the ESRI Metadata Translator's translation engine and not produce a output XML file, provide # instead of a file name.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>A stand-alone XML file that will be created containing the converted metadata.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="logfile" displayname="Log File" datatype="File" direction="Output" expression="logfile" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>A text file that will be created listing the warnings and errors that occurred during the conversion process.</para>
						<para>To export metadata without producing a log file, provide # instead of a file name.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>A text file that will be created listing the warnings and errors that occurred during the conversion process.</para>
					</dialogReference></param></parameters><returnvalues></returnvalues><environments><environment name="Current_workspace" label="Current workspace"></environment></environments><usage><bullet_item>
				<para>When metadata is translated to the ArcGIS metadata format using a "to ESRI-ISO" translation the original document is included in the resulting metadata as an enclosure. You can access the original document from the Metadata Properties dialog box in ArcCatalog.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The metadata content validation messages provided by this tool account for detailed conditions documented in the metadata standard that can't be tested using XML Schema validation. For example, in ISO 19115-based metadata the value of the metadata hierarchy level element determines if a topic category is required or not; this condition can't be tested using an XML Schema. </para><para>A topic category is required if the  item contains spatial data. If the item is identified as spatial data but a topic  category is missing, the validation error reported is Validation failed: em:Resource($a) --&gt; es:not(em:Dataset($a)); em:identificationInfo($a, $b), em:topicCategory($b, $c), em:lookupCodeName($c, gmxRes:MD_TopicCategoryCode). This statement means that the item has to either not be a dataset or a valid topic category code must be provided, and in this case neither is true.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The output files produced by this tool can't be stored in a geodatabase. If the  environment is set to a geodatabase the output files will be stored in a different location, as described below.</para>
				<bulletList>
					<bullet_item>If the  set to a file or personal geodatabase the output files will be stored in the folder in which the geodatabase is stored.</bullet_item>
					<bullet_item>If the  is set to an enterprise or workgroup geodatabase the output files will be stored in the location defined by the system TEMP environment variable. </bullet_item>
				</bulletList>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The Source Metadata parameter has a complex data type. If you use this tool in a model, create a variable for the Source Metadata parameter in ModelBuilder by right-clicking the tool, pointing to Make VariableFrom ParameterSource Metadata.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item><para>Each Translator references files containing validation rules. The message Starting validation indicates validation is beginning using the rules in the specified file. The validation rules defined in ISO19139_min_schema.txt cover the minimum mandatory requirements for ISO metadata, and the rules defined in ESRI-ISO_schema.txt address the remaining metadata elements.  </para><para>  These rules identify if mandatory elements have been provided, if conditional elements are required and provided, and if the value provided in a metadata element is of the correct data type. Validation rules can't detect cardinality issues such as only one purpose element is allowed but two have been provided. Any validation issues found are reported as warnings in the tool's messages. For example, a metadata contact is required in ISO metadata. The following warning indicates complete metadata contact information hasn't been provided: Validation failed: em:Metadata($a) --&gt; em:contact($a, $b), em:CI_ResponsibleParty($b). That is, a metadata contact hasn't been provided at all, or the contact information provided doesn't follow the rules for contacts defined in the CI_ResponsibleParty information class in the ISO 19115 metadata standard.</para>
				<para>After validation the translator generates the output metadata XML file. Cardinality rules are tested at this time. If more than the expected number of elements exist, none of them will be written to the output metadata XML file.   Some validation issues prevent the translator from generating valid output XML and will also reported as warnings in this phase. For example, if a valid metadata contacts hasn't been provided this information can't be included in the output: Error [InvalidForSome]: &lt;MD_Metadata&gt; for-some clause: em:contact(v:Metadata, v:Object) &lt;contact&gt;. That is, one or more contact elements could not be added to the MD_Metadata element in the output XML file; this message is a warning even though it begins with the word error.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The Translator XML files that configure a translation are provided with ArcGIS Desktop in the install location in the Metadata\Translator folder. If you open one of these files in an XML editor you'll see the translator element has an attribute stopOnErrors. This attribute can have one of three values: yes, no, any. When including this tool in a model, you may prefer to copy one of the default Translators and change the stopOnErrors value to produce the desired behavior.</para>
				<bulletList>
					<bullet_item>no—the default value. Translation continues if warnings are encountered. If an error is encountered, translation stops and an incomplete output file will be created; this file will not likely contain well-formed XML. The tool completes successfully.</bullet_item>
					<bullet_item>yes—if a warning or error is encountered, translation stops. An incomplete output file will be created containing the translation results produced before the problem was encountered; this file will not likely contain well-formed XML. The tool completes successfully.</bullet_item>
					<bullet_item>any—if a warning or error is encountered, translation stops. No output file will be created, and the tool will fail. </bullet_item>
				</bulletList>
			</bullet_item></usage><scriptExamples><scriptExample><title>Export ArcGIS metadata</title>
					<para>Exports ArcGIS metadata to an XML file that is formatted correctly for the ISO 19139 metadata standard.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">import arcpy
from arcpy import env
env.workspace = "C:/data"
#set local variables
dir = arcpy.GetInstallInfo("desktop")["InstallDir"]
translator = dir + "Metadata/Translator/ESRI_ISO2ISO19139.xml"
arcpy.ESRITranslator_conversion ("locations.shp", translator, 
    "locations_19139.xml", "locations_19139.txt")
                    </code></scriptExample></scriptExamples></tool></metadata>