<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><Esri><MetaID SYNC="true" /><CreaDate SYNC="true" /><CreaTime SYNC="true" /><SyncOnce SYNC="true">TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate SYNC="true" /><ModTime SYNC="true" /></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle sync="true">Feature To Polygon (Data Management)</resTitle><citRespParty><rpIndName /><rpOrgName>ESRI, Inc.</rpOrgName><rpPosName /><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint><city>Redlands</city><adminArea>California</adminArea><postCode>92373 - 8100</postCode><eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd><country>United States</country></cntAddress><cntPhone><voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum><faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum></cntPhone></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd>010</RoleCd></role></citRespParty></idCitation><idAbs>
			<para> Creates a feature class containing polygons generated from areas enclosed by input line or polygon features.</para>
		</idAbs><descKeys KeyTypCd="005"><keyTyp><keyTyp>005</keyTyp></keyTyp><keyword>Area</keyword><keyword>Change</keyword><keyword>Close</keyword><keyword>Conversion</keyword><keyword>Convert</keyword><keyword>Create Areas</keyword><keyword>Geometry</keyword><keyword>Line</keyword><keyword>Overlay</keyword><keyword>Polygon Feature Class From Lines</keyword><keyword>Region</keyword><keyword>Transform</keyword><keyword>Vector</keyword><keyword>Zone</keyword></descKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName sync="true">ArcToolBox Tool</formatName></distorFormat><distorTran><onLineSrc><linkage /><protocol /><onFunct><onFunctCd /></onFunct></onLineSrc></distorTran></distributor></distInfo><metainfo><metd Sync="TRUE" /></metainfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE" /><tool name="FeatureToPolygon" displayname="Feature To Polygon (Data Management)" toolboxalias="management" softwarerestriction="none"><summary>
			<para> Creates a feature class containing polygons generated from areas enclosed by input line or polygon features.</para>
		</summary><alink_name>FeatureToPolygon_management</alink_name><toolIllust type="dialog" src="ARCTOOLBOXHELP/FeatureToPolygon_management_v.png" alt="Feature To Polygon illustration" /><toolIllust type="illustration" src="FeatureToPolygon_management_h.png" alt="Feature To Polygon" /><parameters><param sync="true" name="in_features" displayname="Input Features" datatype="Feature Layer" direction="Input" expression="[in_features,...]" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para> The input features that can be line or polygon, or both.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para> The input features that can be line or polygon, or both.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="out_feature_class" displayname="Output Feature Class" datatype="Feature Class" direction="Output" expression="out_feature_class" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para> The output polygon feature class.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para> The output polygon feature class.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="cluster_tolerance" displayname="XY Tolerance" datatype="Linear unit" direction="Input" expression="cluster_tolerance" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>The minimum distance separating all feature coordinates, and the distance a coordinate can move in X, Y, or both during spatial computation. The default XY tolerance is set to 0.001 meter or its equivalent in feature units.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The minimum distance separating all feature coordinates, and the distance a coordinate can move in X, Y, or both during spatial computation. The default XY tolerance is set to 0.001 meter or its equivalent in feature units.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="attributes" displayname="Preserve attributes" datatype="Boolean" direction="Output" expression="attributes" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specifies whether to preserve the input attribute schema or the attribures from label features in the output feature class, or omit any input attributes in the output feature class. This parameter does not work.  It will not be removed for backward compatibility of scripts or models. The output attribute schema and field values for certain input combinations may be produced as described in the usage notes; most of them are unintended. </para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>ATTRIBUTES—Preserves the input attribute schema or the attribures from label features, if provided, in the output features. This is the default.</bullet_item><bullet_item>NO_ATTRIBUTES—Omits any input attributes in the output feature class.</bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Specifies whether to preserve the input attribute schema or the attributes from label features in the output feature class, or omit any input attributes in the output feature class. This parameter does not work and should not be used. It will not be removed for backward compatibility of scripts or models. The output attribute schema and field values for certain input combinations may be produced as described in the usage notes; most of them are unintended. </para>
						<bulletList>
							<bullet_item>Checked—Preserves the input attribute schema or the attribures from label features, if provided, in the output features. This is the default.</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>Unchecked—Omits any input attributes in the output feature class.</bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="label_features" displayname="Label Features" datatype="Feature Layer" direction="Input" expression="label_features" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>The optional input point features that hold the attributes to be transferred to the output polygon features.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The optional input point features that hold the attributes to be transferred to the output polygon features.</para>
					</dialogReference></param></parameters><returnvalues></returnvalues><environments><environment name="Current_workspace" label="Current workspace">
						
					</environment><environment name="Scratch_workspace" label="Scratch workspace">
						
					</environment><environment name="Default_output_Z_value" label="Default output Z value">
						
					</environment><environment name="M_resolution" label="M resolution">
						
					</environment><environment name="M_tolerance" label="M tolerance">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_M_domain" label="Output M domain">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_Z_domain" label="Output Z domain">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_coordinate_system" label="Output coordinate system">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_extent" label="Output extent">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_has_M_values" label="Output has M values">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_has_Z_values" label="Output has Z values">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_spatial_grid_1_2_3" label="Output spatial grid 1 2 3">
						
					</environment><environment name="XY_resolution" label="XY resolution">
						
					</environment><environment name="XY_tolerance" label="XY tolerance">
						
					</environment><environment name="Z_resolution" label="Z resolution">
						
					</environment><environment name="Z_tolerance" label="Z tolerance">
						
					</environment></environments><usage><bullet_item>
				<para>Where one or more input features form a closed area, a new polygon feature will be constructed and written to the output feature class. The output attributes will vary depending on the Preserve attributes option on the dialog box (the attributes parameter in scripting) and the Label Features option on the dialog box (the label_features parameter in scripting).</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>When multiple feature classes or layers are specified in the list of input features, the order of the entries in the list does not affect the output feature type, but the spatial reference of the top entry on the tool dialog box (the first entry in scripting) in the list will be used during processing and set to the output.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>Parametric (true) curves in the input features will remain true curves in the output polygons, even if they are split. This does not apply to shapefile data.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The Preserve attributes parameter (the attributes parameter in scripting)  does not work and should not be used. It will not be removed for backward compatibility of scripts or models. The output attribute schema and field values for certain input combinations may be produced as described below; most of them are unintended.</para><para>If the Preserve attributes option on the dialog box is checked (the attributes parameter is set to ATTRIBUTES in scripting), the output attributes schema and field values will depend on whether the label features (points) are provided in the following ways:</para>
				<bulletList>
					<bullet_item> If no label features are provided, the attribute schema (field names and properties, not field values) from each input entry will be maintained in the output in the order they appear in the input list. A new field, FID_xxx, where xxx is the source feature class name of a particular input entry, will be added to the output for each input entry and set to the value of -1. All other fields will have zero or null values.</bullet_item>
					<bullet_item>If label features are provided, none of the input attribute schemas will be maintained in the output feature class; only the attributes of the label features will be included in the output feature class. If an output polygon contains a label feature, it will have field values from that label feature; If an output polygon contains more than one label feature, it will have field values from one of them; otherwise, it will have zero or null field values.</bullet_item>
				</bulletList>
				<para>If the Preserve attributes option on the dialog box is unchecked (the attributes parameter is set to NO_ATTRIBUTES in scripting), none of the input attribute schemas or attributes from label features will be maintained in the output feature class.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para> Where input polygon features are broken into smaller output polygon features, the  tool can be used to transfer attributes from the input polygon features to the resulting polygon features.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>This tool will use a tiling process to handle very large datasets for better performance and scalability. For more details, see .</para>
			</bullet_item></usage><scriptExamples><scriptExample><title>FeatureToPolygon Example 1 (Python window)</title>
					<para>The following Python window script demonstrates how to use the FeatureToPolygon function in immediate mode.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">import arcpy
from arcpy import env
env.workspace = "C:/data"
arcpy.FeatureToPolygon_management(["mainroads.shp","streets.shp"],
                                  "c:/output/output.gdb/streetblocks",
                                  "", "NO_ATTRIBUTES", "")
                    </code></scriptExample><scriptExample><title>FeatureToPolygon Example 2 (stand-alone script)</title>
					<para>The following stand-alone script is a simple example of how to apply the FeatureToPolygon function in a scripting environment.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve"># Name: FeatureToPolygon_Example2.py
# Description: Use FeatureToPolygon function to construct habitat areas
#              from park boundaries and rivers.
# Author: ESRI

# import system modules 
import arcpy
from arcpy import env

# Set environment settings
env.workspace = "C:/data/parks_analysis.gdb"

# Set local parameters
inFeatures = ["park_boundaries", "rivers"]
outFeatureClass = "c:/output/output.gdb/habitat_areas"
clusTol = "0.05 Meters"

# Use the FeatureToPolygon function to form new areas
arcpy.FeatureToPolygon_management(inFeatures, outFeatureClass, clusTol,
                                  "NO_ATTRIBUTES", "")
                    </code></scriptExample></scriptExamples></tool></metadata>