<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><Esri><MetaID SYNC="true" /><CreaDate SYNC="true" /><CreaTime SYNC="true" /><SyncOnce SYNC="true">TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate SYNC="true" /><ModTime SYNC="true" /></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle sync="true">Hot Spot Analysis (Getis-Ord Gi*) (Spatial Statistics)</resTitle><citRespParty><rpIndName /><rpOrgName>ESRI, Inc.</rpOrgName><rpPosName /><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint><city>Redlands</city><adminArea>California</adminArea><postCode>92373 - 8100</postCode><eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd><country>United States</country></cntAddress><cntPhone><voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum><faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum></cntPhone></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd>010</RoleCd></role></citRespParty></idCitation><idAbs>
			<para>Given a set of weighted features, identifies statistically significant hot spots and cold spots using the Getis-Ord Gi* statistic.</para>
			
		</idAbs><descKeys KeyTypCd="005"><keyTyp><keyTyp>005</keyTyp></keyTyp><keyword>Cold</keyword><keyword>Distribution</keyword><keyword>Geographic</keyword><keyword>High</keyword><keyword>Hot Spot</keyword><keyword>Hotspot</keyword><keyword>Local</keyword><keyword>Low</keyword><keyword>Point Pattern Analysis</keyword><keyword>Random</keyword><keyword>Resource Allocation</keyword><keyword>Value</keyword></descKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName sync="true">ArcToolBox Tool</formatName></distorFormat><distorTran><onLineSrc><linkage /><protocol /><onFunct><onFunctCd /></onFunct></onLineSrc></distorTran></distributor></distInfo><metainfo><metd Sync="TRUE" /></metainfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE" /><tool name="HotSpots" displayname="Hot Spot Analysis (Getis-Ord Gi*) (Spatial Statistics)" toolboxalias="stats" softwarerestriction="none"><summary>
			<para>Given a set of weighted features, identifies statistically significant hot spots and cold spots using the Getis-Ord Gi* statistic.</para>
			
		</summary><alink_name>HotSpots_stats</alink_name><toolIllust type="dialog" src="ARCTOOLBOXHELP/HotSpots_stats_v.png" alt="Hot Spot Analysis illustration" /><toolIllust type="illustration" src="HotSpots_stats_h.png" alt="Hot Spot Analysis illustration" /><parameters><param sync="true" name="Input_Feature_Class" displayname="Input Feature Class" datatype="Feature Layer" direction="Input" expression="Input_Feature_Class" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The feature class for which hot spot analysis will be performed.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The feature class for which hot spot analysis will be performed.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Input_Field" displayname="Input Field" datatype="Field" direction="Input" expression="Input_Field" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The numeric count field (number of victims, crimes, jobs, and so on) to be evaluated.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The numeric count field (number of victims, crimes, jobs, and so on) to be evaluated.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Output_Feature_Class" displayname="Output Feature Class" datatype="Feature Class" direction="Output" expression="Output_Feature_Class" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The output feature class to receive the z-score and p-value results.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The output feature class to receive the z-score and p-value results.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Conceptualization_of_Spatial_Relationships" displayname="Conceptualization of Spatial Relationships" datatype="String" direction="Input" expression="Conceptualization_of_Spatial_Relationships" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specifies how spatial relationships among features are conceptualized.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>INVERSE_DISTANCE—Nearby neighboring features have a larger influence  on the  computations for a target feature than features that are far away.</bullet_item><bullet_item>INVERSE_DISTANCE_SQUARED—Same as INVERSE_DISTANCE except that the slope is sharper so influence drops off more quickly and only a target feature's closest neighbors will exert substantial influence on  computations for that feature. </bullet_item><bullet_item>FIXED_DISTANCE_BAND—Each feature is analyzed within the context of neighboring features.  Neighboring features inside the specified critical distance receive a weight of 1,  and exert influence on computations for the target feature.  Neighboring features outside the critical distance receive a weight of zero and have no  influence on a target feature's computations. </bullet_item><bullet_item>ZONE_OF_INDIFFERENCE—Features within the specified critical distance of a target feature receive a weight of 1 and influence computations for that feature. Once the critical distance is exceeded, weights (and the influence a neighboring feature has on target feature computations) diminish with distance. </bullet_item><bullet_item>POLYGON_CONTIGUITY_(FIRST_ORDER)—Only neighboring polygon features that share a boundary will influence computations for the target polygon feature. (Requires an ArcInfo license) </bullet_item><bullet_item>GET_SPATIAL_WEIGHTS_FROM_FILE—Spatial relationships are defined in a spatial weights file. The path to the spatial weights file is specified in the Weights Matrix File parameter. </bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Specifies how spatial relationships among features are conceptualized.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>INVERSE_DISTANCE—Nearby neighboring features have a larger influence  on the  computations for a target feature than features that are far away.</bullet_item><bullet_item>INVERSE_DISTANCE_SQUARED—Same as INVERSE_DISTANCE except that the slope is sharper so influence drops off more quickly and only a target feature's closest neighbors will exert substantial influence on  computations for that feature. </bullet_item><bullet_item>FIXED_DISTANCE_BAND—Each feature is analyzed within the context of neighboring features.  Neighboring features inside the specified critical distance receive a weight of 1,  and exert influence on computations for the target feature.  Neighboring features outside the critical distance receive a weight of zero and have no  influence on a target feature's computations. </bullet_item><bullet_item>ZONE_OF_INDIFFERENCE—Features within the specified critical distance of a target feature receive a weight of 1 and influence computations for that feature. Once the critical distance is exceeded, weights (and the influence a neighboring feature has on target feature computations) diminish with distance. </bullet_item><bullet_item>POLYGON_CONTIGUITY_(FIRST_ORDER)—Only neighboring polygon features that share a boundary will influence computations for the target polygon feature. (Requires an ArcInfo license) </bullet_item><bullet_item>GET_SPATIAL_WEIGHTS_FROM_FILE—Spatial relationships are defined in a spatial weights file. The path to the spatial weights file is specified in the Weights Matrix File parameter. </bullet_item></bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Distance_Method" displayname="Distance Method" datatype="String" direction="Input" expression="Distance_Method" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specifies how distances are calculated from each feature to neighboring features.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>EUCLIDEAN_DISTANCE—The straight-line distance between two points (as the crow flies) </bullet_item><bullet_item>MANHATTAN_DISTANCE—The distance between two points measured along axes at right angles (city block); calculated by summing the (absolute) difference between the x- and y-coordinates </bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Specifies how distances are calculated from each feature to neighboring features.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>EUCLIDEAN_DISTANCE—The straight-line distance between two points (as the crow flies) </bullet_item><bullet_item>MANHATTAN_DISTANCE—The distance between two points measured along axes at right angles (city block); calculated by summing the (absolute) difference between the x- and y-coordinates </bullet_item></bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Standardization" displayname="Standardization" datatype="String" direction="Input" expression="Standardization" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>Row standardization is recommended whenever the distribution of your features is potentially biased due to sampling design or an imposed aggregation scheme.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>NONE—No standardization of spatial weights is applied. </bullet_item><bullet_item>ROW—Spatial weights are standardized; each weight is divided by its row sum (the sum of the weights of all neighboring features). </bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Row standardization is recommended whenever the distribution of your features is potentially biased due to sampling design or an imposed aggregation scheme.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>NONE—No standardization of spatial weights is applied. </bullet_item><bullet_item>ROW—Spatial weights are standardized; each weight is divided by its row sum (the sum of the weights of all neighboring features). </bullet_item></bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Distance_Band_or_Threshold_Distance" displayname="Distance Band or Threshold Distance" datatype="Double" direction="Input" expression="Distance_Band_or_Threshold_Distance" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specifies a cutoff distance for Inverse Distance and Fixed Distance options. Features outside the specified cutoff for a target feature are ignored in analyses for that feature. However, for Zone of Indifference, the influence of features outside the given distance is reduced with distance, while those inside the distance threshold are equally considered. The value entered should match that of the output coordinate system.</para>
						<para>For the Inverse Distance conceptualizations of spatial relationships, a value of 0 indicates that no threshold distance is applied; when this parameter is left blank, a default threshold value is computed and applied.    This default value is the Euclidean distance that ensures every feature has at least one neighbor.</para>
						<para>This parameter has no effect when Polygon Contiguity or Get Spatial Weights From File spatial conceptualizations are selected.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Specifies a cutoff distance for Inverse Distance and Fixed Distance options. Features outside the specified cutoff for a target feature are ignored in analyses for that feature. However, for Zone of Indifference, the influence of features outside the given distance is reduced with distance, while those inside the distance threshold are equally considered. The value entered should match that of the output coordinate system.</para>
						<para>For the Inverse Distance conceptualizations of spatial relationships, a value of 0 indicates that no threshold distance is applied; when this parameter is left blank, a default threshold value is computed and applied.    This default value is the Euclidean distance that ensures every feature has at least one neighbor.</para>
						<para>This parameter has no effect when Polygon Contiguity or Get Spatial Weights From File spatial conceptualizations are selected.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Self_Potential_Field" displayname="Self Potential Field" datatype="Field" direction="Input" expression="Self_Potential_Field" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>The field representing self-potential: The distance or weight between a feature and itself.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The field representing self-potential: The distance or weight between a feature and itself.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Weights_Matrix_File" displayname="Weights Matrix File" datatype="File" direction="Input" expression="Weights_Matrix_File" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>The path to a file containing spatial weights that define spatial relationships among features.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The path to a file containing spatial weights that define spatial relationships among features.</para>
					</dialogReference></param></parameters><returnvalues></returnvalues><environments><environment name="Output_coordinate_system" label="Output coordinate system">Feature geometry is projected to the Output Coordinate System prior to analysis, so values entered for the Distance Band/Threshold Distance parameter should match those specified in the Output Coordinate System. All mathematical computations are based on the Output Coordinate System spatial reference.</environment><environment name="Current_workspace" label="Current workspace"></environment><environment name="Scratch_workspace" label="Scratch workspace"></environment><environment name="Qualified_field_names" label="Qualified field names"></environment><environment name="Output_has_M_values" label="Output has M values"></environment><environment name="Output_has_Z_values" label="Output has Z values"></environment><environment name="Default_output_Z_value" label="Default output Z value"></environment></environments><usage><bullet_item>
				<para>This tool identifies statistically significant spatial clusters of high values (hot spots) and low values (cold spots). It creates a new Output Feature Class with a z-score and p-value for each feature in the Input Feature Class. It also returns the z-score and p-value field names as derived output values for potential use in custom models and scripts. </para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The z-scores and p-values are measures of statistical significance which tell you whether or not to reject the null hypothesis, feature by feature. In effect, they indicate whether the observed spatial clustering of high or low values is more pronounced than one would expect in a random distribution of those same values. </para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>A high z-score and small p-value for a feature indicates a spatial clustering of high values. A low negative z-score and small p-value indicates a spatial clustering of low values. The higher (or lower) the z-score, the more intense the clustering. A z-score near zero indicates no apparent spatial clustering.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The z-score is based on the randomization null hypothesis computation. For more information on z-scores, see </para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>Calculations based on either Euclidean or Manhattan distance require  to accurately measure distances.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>For line and polygon features, feature centroids are used in distance computations. For multipoints, polylines, or polygons with multiple parts, the centroid is computed using the weighted mean center of all feature parts. The weighting for point features is 1, for line features is length, and for polygon features is area.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The Input Field should contain a variety of values. The math for this statistic requires some variation in the variable being analyzed; it cannot solve if all input values are 1, for example. If you want to use this tool to analyze the spatial pattern of incident data, consider  .</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>Your choice for the Conceptualization of Spatial Relationships parameter should reflect inherent relationships among the features you are analyzing. The more realistically you can model how features interact with each other in space, the more accurate your results are. . Here are some additional tips: <bulletList>
						<bullet_item>
							FIXED_DISTANCE_BAND<para> The default value for the Distance Band or Threshold Distance parameter ensures that each feature has at least one neighbor, and this is important. But often, this default will <bold>not</bold> be the most  to use for your analysis.             </para><para> to learn more about the Distance Band or Threshold Distance parameter.</para>
						</bullet_item>
						<bullet_item>INVERSE_DISTANCE or INVERSE_DISTANCE_SQUARED<para>When 0 is entered for the Distance Band or Threshold Distance parameter, all features are considered neighbors of all other features; when this parameter is left blank, the default threshold distance is applied. </para><para>Weights for distances less than 1 become unstable. The weighting for features separated by less than one unit of distance (common with  projections) is 1. 
									<para>Analysis on features with a  projection is not recommended when you select any of the inverse distance-based spatial conceptualization methods (INVERSE_DISTANCE, INVERSE_DISTANCE_SQUARED, or ZONE_OF_INDIFFERENCE).</para>
								</para><para>For these Inverse Distance options, any two points that are coincident are given a weight of 1 to avoid zero division. This ensures features are not excluded from analysis.</para></bullet_item>
					</bulletList></para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>Additional options for the Conceptualization of Spatial Relationships parameter are available using the  or  tools.  To take advantage of these additional options, use one of these tools to construct the  prior to analysis; select GET_SPATIAL_WEIGHTS_FROM_FILE for the Conceptualization of Spatial Relationships parameter; and, for the Weights Matrix File parameter, specify the path to the spatial weights file you created.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>Map layers can be used to define the Input Feature Class. When using a layer with a selection, only the selected features are included in the analysis.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item><para>If you provide a Weights Matrix File with a .SWM or .swm extention, this tool is expecting a spatial weights matrix file created using either the  or  tools.  Otherwise this tool is expecting an . In some cases, behavior is different depending on which type of spatial weights matrix file you use:<bulletList><bullet_item>ASCII formatted spatial weights matrix files:Weights are used AS-IS.  Missing feature-to-feature relationships are treated as zeros.  The default weight for  is zero, unless you specify a Self-Potential field value, or include self-potential weights explicitly.If the weights are row standardized, results will likely be incorrect for analyses on selection sets.  If you need to run your analysis on a selection set, convert the ASCII spatial weights file to a .swm file by reading the ASCII data into a table, then using the CONVERT_TABLE option with the  tool.</bullet_item><bullet_item>.SWM formatted spatial weights matrix fileIf the weights are row standardized, they will be re-standardized for selection sets.  Otherwise weights are used AS-IS.The default weight for  is one, unless you specify a Self-Potential field value. </bullet_item></bulletList></para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>Running your analysis with an  is memory intensive.  For analyses on more than about 5000 features, consider converting your ASCII formatted spatial weights matrix file into a .  First put your ASCII weights into a  table (using Excel, for example).  Next run the   tool using CONVERT_TABLE for the Conceptualization of Spatial Relationships parameter.  The output will be a .swm formatted spatial weights matrix file. </para></bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>When this tool runs in ArcMap, the Output Feature Class is automatically added to the Table of Contents (TOC) with default rendering applied to the z-score field. The hot to cold rendering applied is defined by a layer file in &lt;ArcGIS&gt;/ArcToolbox/Templates/Layers. You can reapply the default rendering, if needed, by  the template layer symbology.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The  help topic provides additional information about this tool's parameters.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				
					<para>When using shapefiles, keep in mind that they cannot store null values. Tools or other procedures that create shapefiles from non-shapefile inputs may store or interpret null values as zero. This can lead to unexpected results.  See also .</para>
				
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para><para>In ArcGIS 9.2, the Global standardization option was removed. Global standardization returns the same results as no standardization. Models built with previous versions of ArcGIS that use the Global standardization option may need to be rebuilt.</para></para>
			</bullet_item></usage><scriptExamples><scriptExample><title>HotSpotAnalysis Example (Python Window)</title>
					<para>The following Python Window script demonstrates how to use the HotSpotAnalysis tool.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">import arcpy
arcpy.env.workspace = "C:/data"
arcpy.HotSpots_stats("911Count.shp", "ICOUNT", "911HotSpots.shp","GET_SPATIAL_WEIGHTS_FROM_FILE","EUCLIDEAN_DISTANCE", "NONE","#", "#", "euclidean6Neighs.swm")
                    </code></scriptExample><scriptExample><title>HotSpotAnalysis Example (Stand-alone Python script)</title>
					<para>The following stand-alone Python script demonstrates how to use the HotSpotAnalysis tool.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">
# Analyze the spatial distribution of 911 calls in a metropolitan area
# using the Hot-Spot Analysis Tool (Local Gi*)

# Import system modules
import arcpy

# Set geoprocessor object property to overwrite existing output, by default
arcpy.gp.overwriteOutput = True

# Local variables...
workspace = "C:/Data"

try:
    # Set the current workspace (to avoid having to specify the full path to the feature classes each time)
    arcpy.env.workspace = workspace

    # Copy the input feature class and integrate the points to snap
    # together at 500 feet
    # Process: Copy Features and Integrate
    cf = arcpy.CopyFeatures_management("911Calls.shp", "911Copied.shp",
                         "#", 0, 0, 0)

    integrate = arcpy.Integrate_management("911Copied.shp #", "500 Feet")

    # Use Collect Events to count the number of calls at each location
    # Process: Collect Events
    ce = arcpy.CollectEvents_stats("911Copied.shp", "911Count.shp", "Count", "#")

    # Add a unique ID field to the count feature class
    # Process: Add Field and Calculate Field
    af = arcpy.AddField_management("911Count.shp", "MyID", "LONG", "#", "#", "#", "#",
                     "NON_NULLABLE", "NON_REQUIRED", "#",
                     "911Count.shp")
    
    cf = arcpy.CalculateField_management("911Count.shp", "MyID", "[FID]", "VB")

    # Create Spatial Weights Matrix for Calculations
    # Process: Generate Spatial Weights Matrix... 
    swm = arcpy.GenerateSpatialWeightsMatrix_stats("911Count.shp", "MYID",
                        "euclidean6Neighs.swm",
                        "K_NEAREST_NEIGHBORS",
                        "#", "#", "#", 6,
                        "NO_STANDARDIZATION") 

    # Hot Spot Analysis of 911 Calls
    # Process: Hot Spot Analysis (Getis-Ord Gi*)
    hs = arcpy.HotSpots_stats("911Count.shp", "ICOUNT", "911HotSpots.shp", 
                     "GET_SPATIAL_WEIGHTS_FROM_FILE",
                     "EUCLIDEAN_DISTANCE", "NONE",
                     "#", "#", "euclidean6Neighs.swm")

except:
    # If an error occurred when running the tool, print out the error message.
    print arcpy.GetMessages()

                    </code></scriptExample></scriptExamples></tool></metadata>