<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><Esri><MetaID SYNC="true" /><CreaDate SYNC="true" /><CreaTime SYNC="true" /><SyncOnce SYNC="true">TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate SYNC="true" /><ModTime SYNC="true" /></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle sync="true">Synchronize Metadata (Conversion)</resTitle><citRespParty><rpIndName /><rpOrgName>ESRI, Inc.</rpOrgName><rpPosName /><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint><city>Redlands</city><adminArea>California</adminArea><postCode>92373 - 8100</postCode><eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd><country>United States</country></cntAddress><cntPhone><voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum><faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum></cntPhone></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd>010</RoleCd></role></citRespParty></idCitation><idAbs>
			<para> Automatically updates an ArcGIS item's metadata with the current properties of the item. </para>
			<para>For example, if the metadata describes the item as having one projection but the item's projection has changed since the last automatic update, the old projection information in the metadata will be replaced with the new projection information. </para>
			<para>The item's metadata must be stored in the ArcGIS metadata format; otherwise, the metadata will not be synchronized.</para><para>If a property was set using ArcGIS Desktop 9.3.1 or earlier to prevent ArcGIS from automatically updating this specific item's metadata with the item's properties, it will be ignored in the current release. ArcGIS metadata will always be synchronized with the item it descibes.</para></idAbs><descKeys KeyTypCd="005"><keyTyp><keyTyp>005</keyTyp></keyTyp><keyword>Change</keyword><keyword>Convert</keyword><keyword>Copy</keyword><keyword>Export</keyword><keyword>Format</keyword><keyword>Import</keyword><keyword>Intrinsic</keyword><keyword>Make</keyword><keyword>Match</keyword><keyword>Properties</keyword><keyword>Standard</keyword><keyword>Style</keyword><keyword>Transfer</keyword><keyword>Turn</keyword><keyword>Update</keyword><keyword>Xml</keyword></descKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName sync="true">ArcToolBox Tool</formatName></distorFormat><distorTran><onLineSrc><linkage /><protocol /><onFunct><onFunctCd /></onFunct></onLineSrc></distorTran></distributor></distInfo><metainfo><metd Sync="TRUE" /></metainfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE" /><tool name=" SynchronizeMetadata " displayname="Synchronize Metadata (Conversion)" toolboxalias="conversion" softwarerestriction="none"><summary>
			<para> Automatically updates an ArcGIS item's metadata with the current properties of the item. </para>
			<para>For example, if the metadata describes the item as having one projection but the item's projection has changed since the last automatic update, the old projection information in the metadata will be replaced with the new projection information. </para>
			<para>The item's metadata must be stored in the ArcGIS metadata format; otherwise, the metadata will not be synchronized.</para><para>If a property was set using ArcGIS Desktop 9.3.1 or earlier to prevent ArcGIS from automatically updating this specific item's metadata with the item's properties, it will be ignored in the current release. ArcGIS metadata will always be synchronized with the item it descibes.</para></summary><alink_name> SynchronizeMetadata _conversion</alink_name><parameters><param sync="true" name="source" displayname="Source Metadata" datatype="Data Element; Layer" direction="Input" expression="source" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The item whose metadata will be synchronized.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The item whose metadata will be synchronized.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="synctype" displayname="Synchronize Type" datatype="String" direction="Input" expression="synctype" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The type of synchronization that will take place.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>ALWAYS—Properties of the source item are always added to or updated in its metadata. Metadata will be created if it doesn't already exist.  This is the deault.</bullet_item><bullet_item>ACCESSED—Properties of the source item are added to or updated in its metadata when it is accessed. Metadata will be created if it doesn't already exist.</bullet_item><bullet_item>CREATED—Metadata will be created and properties of the source item will be added to it if the item doesn't already have metadata. </bullet_item><bullet_item>NOT_CREATED—Properties of the source item are added to or updated in existing metadata. </bullet_item><bullet_item>OVERWRITE—The same as "ALWAYS" except all information that can be recorded automatically in the metadata will be recorded. Any properties typed in by a person will be replaced with the item's actual properties.</bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The type of synchronization that will take place.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>ALWAYS—Properties of the source item are always added to or updated in its metadata. Metadata will be created if it doesn't already exist.  This is the deault.</bullet_item><bullet_item>ACCESSED—Properties of the source item are added to or updated in its metadata when it is accessed. Metadata will be created if it doesn't already exist.</bullet_item><bullet_item>CREATED—Metadata will be created and properties of the source item will be added to it if the item doesn't already have metadata. </bullet_item><bullet_item>NOT_CREATED—Properties of the source item are added to or updated in existing metadata. </bullet_item><bullet_item>OVERWRITE—The same as "ALWAYS" except all information that can be recorded automatically in the metadata will be recorded. Any properties typed in by a person will be replaced with the item's actual properties.</bullet_item></bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param></parameters><returnvalues></returnvalues><environments><environment name="Current_workspace" label="Current workspace"></environment></environments><usage><bullet_item><para>By default, metadata is automatically updated when anyone who has write access to the ArcGIS item views its metadata. Metadata can also be synchronized by running this tool. The option to turn off synchronization when you view metadata doesn't affect how this tool operates.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>If someone edits an ArcGIS item's data or changes its properties and does not view the metadata, the properties recorded in the metadata are out of date with the actual properties of the item. If you were to use or publish the item's metadata in this state without first running this tool the information in the metadata would not be current.</para>
				<para>The , , , and  tools all update the metadata automatically before performing other operations. The  and  tools automatically update the metadata after performing other operations. </para><para>If your organization's metadata workflow incorporates other operations or tools that don't synchronize the metadata you may want to write a Python script that would run this tool as needed. For example, if you use a utility that publishes metadata for all items in a geodatabase to a metadata catalog nightly, ideally you would synchronize the metadata content nightly before publishing to  ensure the published information is always current.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item><para>If you try to synchronize a stand-alone metadata XML file, the tool will complete successfully but the XML file will remain unchanged. </para></bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>The Source Metadata parameter has a complex data type. If you use this tool in a model, create a variable for the Source Metadata parameter in ModelBuilder by right-clicking the tool, pointing to Make VariableFrom ParameterSource Metadata.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para> When using this tool in ModelBuilder, the Output Metadata parameter is derived from the Source Metadata parameter.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>If you do not  have write access to the ArcGIS item or its metadata or the stand-alone metadata XML file that you are trying to modify, this tool will complete successfully but the item's original metadata will remain unchanged.</para>
				
			</bullet_item></usage><scriptExamples><scriptExample><title>Synchronize an ArcGIS item's metadata</title>
					<para>Metadata for an ArcGIS item is updated to contain the current properties of the item only if the item already has metadata; new metadata won't be created.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">import arcpy
from arcpy import env
env.workspace = "C:/data/data.gdb"
arcpy.SynchronizeMetadata_conversion("vegetation", "NOT_CREATED")
                    </code></scriptExample></scriptExamples></tool></metadata>