<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><Esri><MetaID SYNC="true" /><CreaDate SYNC="true" /><CreaTime SYNC="true" /><SyncOnce SYNC="true">TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate SYNC="true" /><ModTime SYNC="true" /></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle sync="true"> Consolidate Layer  (Data Management)</resTitle><citRespParty><rpIndName /><rpOrgName>ESRI, Inc.</rpOrgName><rpPosName /><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint><city>Redlands</city><adminArea>California</adminArea><postCode>92373 - 8100</postCode><eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd><country>United States</country></cntAddress><cntPhone><voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum><faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum></cntPhone></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd>010</RoleCd></role></citRespParty></idCitation><idAbs>
			<para> Consolidates one or more layers by copying all data and referenced data sources  into a single folder. </para>
		</idAbs><descKeys KeyTypCd="005"><keyTyp><keyTyp>005</keyTyp></keyTyp><keyword>Add</keyword><keyword>Aggregate</keyword><keyword>Amalgamate</keyword><keyword>Assemble</keyword><keyword>Bundle</keyword><keyword>Centralize</keyword><keyword>Collect</keyword><keyword>Copy</keyword><keyword>Gather</keyword><keyword>Group</keyword><keyword>Incorporate</keyword><keyword>Move</keyword><keyword>Share</keyword><keyword>Together</keyword></descKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName sync="true">ArcToolBox Tool</formatName></distorFormat><distorTran><onLineSrc><linkage /><protocol /><onFunct><onFunctCd /></onFunct></onLineSrc></distorTran></distributor></distInfo><metainfo><metd Sync="TRUE" /></metainfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE" /><tool name="ConsolidateLayer " displayname=" Consolidate Layer  (Data Management)" toolboxalias="management" softwarerestriction="none"><summary>
			<para> Consolidates one or more layers by copying all data and referenced data sources  into a single folder. </para>
		</summary><alink_name>ConsolidateLayer _management</alink_name><toolIllust type="illustration" src="ConsolidateLayer_management_h.png" alt="Consolidate Layer illustration" /><parameters><param sync="true" name="in_layer" displayname="Input Layer" datatype="Layer" direction="Input" expression="[in_layer,...]" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para> The input layer(s) that will be consolidated.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para> The input layer(s) that will be consolidated.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="output_folder" displayname="Output Folder" datatype="Folder" direction="Output" expression="output_folder" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para> The output folder that will contain the layer files and consolidated data. </para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para> The output folder that will contain the layer files and consolidated data. </para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="convert_data" displayname="Convert Data to File Geodatabase" datatype="Boolean" direction="Input" expression="convert_data" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specifies whether input layers will be converted into file geodatabase or preserve their original format. </para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>CONVERT — Data will be copied to a file geodatabase. </bullet_item><bullet_item>PRESERVE — Data formats will be preserved.  This is the default.</bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Specifies whether input layers will be converted to a file geodatabase or preserve their original format. </para>
						<bulletList>
							<bullet_item>Checked—All data will be converted to a file geodatabase.</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>Unchecked—Data formats will be preserved. This is the default.</bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="convert_arcsde_data" displayname="Convert ArcSDE Data to File Geodatabase" datatype="Boolean" direction="Input" expression="convert_arcsde_data" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specifies whether input layers will be converted into file geodatabase or preserve their original format. </para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>CONVERT_ARCSDE— ArcSDE data will be copied to a file geodatabase. This is the default.</bullet_item><bullet_item>PRESERVE_ARCSDE— ArcSDE data will be preserved and will be referenced in the resulting consolidated folder or package. </bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Specifies whether input ArcSDE layers will be converted into a file geodatabase or will be preserved.   </para>
						<bulletList>
							<bullet_item>Checked—All ArcSDE data will be converted to a file geodatabase. This is the default.</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>Unchecked—ArcSDE data sources will be preserved and will be referenced in the resulting package.</bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="extent" displayname="Extent" datatype="Extent" direction="Input" expression="extent" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specify the extent by manually entering the coordinates in the extent parameter using the format X-Min Y-Min X-Max Y-Max. Additionally, to use the extent of a specific layer, simply add the layer name for the extent parameter.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>MAXOF—Union of inputs</bullet_item><bullet_item>MINOF—Intersection of inputs</bullet_item><bullet_item>DISPLAY—Same as Display</bullet_item><bullet_item>&lt;Layer&gt;—Same as Layer...</bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para> Specify the extent that will be used to select or clip features.</para><bulletList>
							<bullet_item>Default—The extent will be based on the maximum extent of all participating layers. This is the default.</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>Union of Inputs—The maximum extent of all input(s).</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>Intersection of Inputs—The minimum area common to all input(s).</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>As Specified Below—Specify the minimum and maximum extent values.</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>Same as Display—Extent is equal to the dataframe or visible display.</bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="apply_extent_to_arcsde" displayname="Apply Extent to ArcSDE Layers Only" datatype="Boolean" direction="Input" expression="apply_extent_to_arcsde" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specifies the extent that will be used to select ArcSDE data sources.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>ALL — Specified extent is applied to all layers. This is the default.</bullet_item><bullet_item>ARCSDE_ONLY —Specified extent is applied to ArcSDE layers only. </bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Determines whether specified extent will be applied to ArcSDE data sources only.</para>
						<bulletList>
							<bullet_item>Unchecked—Extent will be applied to all layers. This is the default.</bullet_item><bullet_item>Checked—Extent will be applied to ArcSDE layers only. </bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="schema_only" displayname="Schema Only" datatype="Boolean" direction="Input" expression="schema_only" type="Optional"><pythonReference>
						<para>Specifies whether the schema of the input layers will be consolidated or packaged.</para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>ALL  — All features and records will be consolidated or packaged. This is the default.</bullet_item><bullet_item>SCHEMA_ONLY— Only the Schema of input layers will be consolidated pr packaged.</bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>Specifies whether consolidated or packaged layers will only contain the layers' schema.</para><bulletList>
							<bullet_item>Unchecked—All features and records for input layers will be included in the consolidated folder or package. This is the default.</bullet_item><bullet_item>Checked—Only the schema of the layer(s) will be consolidated  or packaged. No features or records will be consolidated or packaged in the output folder.</bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param></parameters><returnvalues></returnvalues><environments><environment name="Current_workspace" label="Current workspace">
						
					</environment></environments><usage><bullet_item><para>When consolidating or packaging layers, the resulting layers will be renamed using the convention <bold>integer + layername</bold> (for example, 001fGDB_Polylayer.lyr).  The numbered sequence is added to maintain the ordering of the layers as they appear in the table of contents.   The lower the number, the higher the layer will appear in the table of contents when the package is unpacked.   </para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>When Convert Data to File Geodatabase is checked<bulletList><bullet_item>Each data source will have a unique file geodatabase created in the consolidated folder.</bullet_item><bullet_item>Compressed raster and vector  formats will be converted to file geodatabase, and  compression will be lost.</bullet_item></bulletList></para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>When Convert Data to File Geodatabase is unchecked<bulletList><bullet_item>The format of the input layers will be preserved with one exception; layers that reference data in a personal geodatabase are always converted to file geodatabase.<bold></bold></bullet_item><bullet_item>Every data source will preserve its original format.   File geodatabases will be consolidated into a version-specific folder, and all other formats will be consolidated in the commonData folder.</bullet_item><bullet_item>Layers that point to ArcSDE data sources will preserve their connection information and remain pointing to the ArcSDE data source in the consolidated folder or package. </bullet_item><bullet_item>ADRG, CADRG, CIB, and RPF raster formats will always convert to file geodatabase rasters. ArcGIS cannot natively write out these formats.  They will always be converted to File Geodatabase rasters for efficiency.</bullet_item><bullet_item>Compressed raster and vector formats will not be clipped, even if an extent is specified in the Extent parameter.  </bullet_item></bulletList>
				</para></bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>For layers that contain a join or participate in a relationship class, all joined or related data sources will be consolidated into the output folder. </para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>For feature layers,   the Extent parameter is used to <bold>select</bold> the features that will be consolidated. For raster layers , the Extent parameter is used to <bold>clip</bold> the raster datasets.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>Some datasets reference other datasets.  For example, you may have a Topology dataset that references four feature classes. Other examples of datasets that reference other datasets include Geometric Networks, Networks, and Locators.  When consolidating or packaging a layer based on these types of datasets, the participating datasets will also be consolidated or packaged.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item><para>The Schema Only parameter, if checked, will only consolidate  the schema of the input data source(s).  A schema is the structure or design of a  feature class or table that consists of field and table definitions, coordinate system properties, symbology, definition queries, and so on.  Data or records will not be consolidated.    </para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>   Data sources that do not support schema only will not be consolidated or packaged.    If the Schema Only parameter  is checked and the tool encounters a layer that is not supported for schema only, a warning message is displayed, and that layer will be skipped.  If the only layer specified is unsupported for schema only, the tool will fail. </para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>Consolidating or packaging Coverage or VPF layers will copy the entire Coverage or VPF dataset into the consolidated folder or package.</para></bullet_item></usage><scriptExamples><scriptExample><title>ConsolidateLayer Example (Python Window)</title>
					<para>The following Python window script demonstrates how to use the ConsolidateLayer tool in immediate mode.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">
import arcpy
arcpy.env.workspace = "C:/arcgis/ArcTutor/BuildingaGeodatabase/Layers" 
arcpy.ConsolidateLayer_management('Parcels.lyr', 'Consolidate_folder', "PRESERVE", "CONVERT_SDE", "#", "ALL","ALL")
                    </code></scriptExample><scriptExample><title>ConsolidateLayer Example 1 (stand-alone Python script)</title>
					<para>Finds and creates individual consolidated folders for all of the layer files that reside in a specified folder.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">
# Name: ConsolidateLayerEx1.py
# Description:  Find all the layer files that reside in a specified folder and create a consolidated folder for each layer file.
# Author: ESRI

# import system modules
import arcpy, os
from arcpy import env

# Set environment settings
env.overwriteOutput = True
env.workspace = "C:/arcgis/ArcTutor/BuildingaGeodatabase/Layers" 
wrksp = env.workspace

# Loop through the workspace, find all the layer files (.lyr) and create a consolidated folder for each 
# layer file found using the same name as the original layer file.
for lyr in arcpy.ListFiles("*.lyr"):
				arcpy.ConsolidateLayer_management(lyr, os.path.splitext(lyr)[0],"PRESERVE", "CONVERT_SDE", "#", "ALL", "ALL")

                    </code></scriptExample><scriptExample><title>ConsolidateLayer Example 2 (stand-alone Python script)</title>
					<para>Finds and creates a single consolidated folder for all of the layer files that reside in a specified workspace.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">
# Name: ConsolidateLayerEx2.py
# Description:  Find all the layer files that reside in a specified folder and create a single 
# consolidated folder that will contain all layers found.
# Author: ESRI

# import system modules
import arcpy, os
from arcpy import env

# Set environment settings
env.overwriteOutput = True
env.workspace = "C:/arcgis/ArcTutor/BuildingaGeodatabase/Layers" 
wrksp = env.workspace

# Find all the layer files (.lyr) in a workspace and create a single consolidated folder
lyrs = arcpy.ListFiles("*.lyr")
arcpy.ConsolidateLayer_management(lyrs, 'all_layers',"PRESERVE", "CONVERT_SDE", "#", "ALL", "ALL")

                    </code></scriptExample></scriptExamples></tool></metadata>