<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><Esri><MetaID SYNC="true" /><CreaDate SYNC="true" /><CreaTime SYNC="true" /><SyncOnce SYNC="true">TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate SYNC="true" /><ModTime SYNC="true" /></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle sync="true"> Import Metadata (Conversion)</resTitle><citRespParty><rpIndName /><rpOrgName>ESRI, Inc.</rpOrgName><rpPosName /><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint><city>Redlands</city><adminArea>California</adminArea><postCode>92373 - 8100</postCode><eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd><country>United States</country></cntAddress><cntPhone><voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum><faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum></cntPhone></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd>010</RoleCd></role></citRespParty></idCitation><idAbs>
			<para> Imports metadata to the target item after converting the source item's metadata to ArcGIS metadata, if appropriate. The source and target may be ArcGIS items or stand-alone metadata XML files. </para>
			<para>This tool processes the source metadata before importing it and updates the target metadata after. Any intrinsic properties of the source item that were added automatically to its metadata by ArcGIS are removed along with any unique  identifiers before converting the information to the ArcGIS metadata format, if necessary. After the imported information is saved, the target item's metadata is automatically updated with its intrinsic properties.</para>
			<para>This tool is useful for copying metadata from one item to another when you start creating its metadata; the imported metadata acts as a template. Using another metadata document as a template can save time if two items share some information such a legal restrictions or a description of the project for which they were created.</para>
			
				<para>Existing metadata will be replaced by the imported metadata.</para>
			
		</idAbs><descKeys KeyTypCd="005"><keyTyp><keyTyp>005</keyTyp></keyTyp><keyword>19139</keyword><keyword>Change</keyword><keyword>Convert</keyword><keyword>Copy</keyword><keyword>Esri-Iso</keyword><keyword>Esriiso</keyword><keyword>Export</keyword><keyword>Fgdc</keyword><keyword>Format</keyword><keyword>Import</keyword><keyword>Iso</keyword><keyword>Make</keyword><keyword>Standard</keyword><keyword>Style</keyword><keyword>Transfer</keyword><keyword>Translate</keyword><keyword>Turn</keyword><keyword>Xml</keyword></descKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName sync="true">ArcToolBox Tool</formatName></distorFormat><distorTran><onLineSrc><linkage /><protocol /><onFunct><onFunctCd /></onFunct></onLineSrc></distorTran></distributor></distInfo><metainfo><metd Sync="TRUE" /></metainfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE" /><tool name=" ImportMetadata " displayname=" Import Metadata (Conversion)" toolboxalias="conversion" softwarerestriction="none"><summary>
			<para> Imports metadata to the target item after converting the source item's metadata to ArcGIS metadata, if appropriate. The source and target may be ArcGIS items or stand-alone metadata XML files. </para>
			<para>This tool processes the source metadata before importing it and updates the target metadata after. Any intrinsic properties of the source item that were added automatically to its metadata by ArcGIS are removed along with any unique  identifiers before converting the information to the ArcGIS metadata format, if necessary. After the imported information is saved, the target item's metadata is automatically updated with its intrinsic properties.</para>
			<para>This tool is useful for copying metadata from one item to another when you start creating its metadata; the imported metadata acts as a template. Using another metadata document as a template can save time if two items share some information such a legal restrictions or a description of the project for which they were created.</para>
			
				<para>Existing metadata will be replaced by the imported metadata.</para>
			
		</summary><alink_name> ImportMetadata _conversion</alink_name><parameters><param sync="true" name="Source_Metadata" displayname="Source Metadata" datatype="Data Element; Layer" direction="Input" expression="Source_Metadata" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The item whose metadata will be imported, or a stand-alone XML file that will be imported.</para>
						<para>If the source item is a stand-alone file it must contain well-formed XML data.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The item whose metadata will be imported, or a stand-alone XML file that will be imported.</para>
						<para>If the source item is a stand-alone file it must contain well-formed XML data.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Import_Type" displayname="Import Type" datatype="String" direction="Input" expression="Import_Type" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The format of the metadata that will be imported. </para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>FROM_ARCGIS—The source metadata is ArcGIS metadata. The metadata won't be converted. </bullet_item><bullet_item>FROM_ESRIISO—The source metadata is ESRI-ISO metadata; that is, it was created using the ISO metadata editor provided with ArcGIS Desktop 9.3.1 and earlier releases. It will be converted to ArcGIS metadata before it is imported. </bullet_item><bullet_item>FROM_FGDC—The source metadata is stored in the FGDC CSDGM metadata standard's XML format. The imported metadata is converted to ArcGIS metadata before it is imported. </bullet_item><bullet_item>FROM_ISO_19139—The source metadata is formatted according  to the ISO 19139 metadata standard. The imported metadata is converted to ArcGIS metadata before it is imported. </bullet_item></bulletList>
						<para>By default, the "FROM_ISO_19139" conversion will be performed.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The format of the metadata that will be imported. </para>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>FROM_ARCGIS—The source metadata is ArcGIS metadata. The metadata won't be converted. </bullet_item><bullet_item>FROM_ESRIISO—The source metadata is ESRI-ISO metadata; that is, it was created using the ISO metadata editor provided with ArcGIS Desktop 9.3.1 and earlier releases. It will be converted to ArcGIS metadata before it is imported. </bullet_item><bullet_item>FROM_FGDC—The source metadata is stored in the FGDC CSDGM metadata standard's XML format. The imported metadata is converted to ArcGIS metadata before it is imported. </bullet_item><bullet_item>FROM_ISO_19139—The source metadata is formatted according  to the ISO 19139 metadata standard. The imported metadata is converted to ArcGIS metadata before it is imported. </bullet_item></bulletList>
						<para>By default, the "FROM_ISO_19139" conversion will be performed.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Target_Metadata" displayname="Target Metadata" datatype="Data Element; Layer" direction="Input" expression="Target_Metadata" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<para>The item to which the metadata will be imported, or a stand-alone XML file that will be replaced.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<para>The item to which the metadata will be imported, or a stand-alone XML file that will be replaced.</para>
					</dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="Enable_automatic_updates" displayname="Enable automatic updates" datatype="Boolean" direction="Input" expression="Enable_automatic_updates" type="Required"><pythonReference>
						<bulletList><bullet_item>ENABLE —Information in the imported metadata describing the item's properties will be modified to contain the actual item properties and additional properties of the item not present in the imported metadata will be added. The default value.</bullet_item><bullet_item>DISABLE— Imported information won't be modified but additional properties of the item not present in the imported metadata will be added.</bullet_item></bulletList>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference>
						<bulletList>
							<bullet_item>Checked—Information in the imported metadata describing the item's properties will be modified to contain the actual item properties. The default value.</bullet_item>
							<bullet_item>Unchecked—Imported information won't be modified but additional properties of the item not present in the imported metadata may be added.</bullet_item>
						</bulletList>
					</dialogReference></param></parameters><returnvalues></returnvalues><environments><environment name="Current_workspace" label="Current workspace"></environment></environments><usage><bullet_item>
				<para>Metadata may include unique identifiers that help to manage documents in a metadata catalog. As a precaution, this tool removes any unique identifiers in the source metadata before importing it. This is the desired behavior if your intention is to copy common information from one item to another. If many items share the same identifier it is no longer unique, and problems can arise if the metadata is later published. </para>
				<para>However, if you modify a source item's metadata using the  tool, for example, to update contact information, and need to import the resulting XML file back to the source item, use  instead. In this case it is not appropriate to remove the source item's unique identifier or alter its content before importing the metadata.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>After importing, the metadata is updated automatically to include the current properties of the target item. By default, the Enable automatic updates parameter is checked. With this option, the imported information will be modified to contain the actual properties of the item. Any properties not already recorded in the metadata will be added. This ensures the metadata will remain current as the item changes. For example, if the imported metadata included a title describing another item, that title will be replaced with the target item's name. You can edit the title later so it better describes the target item.</para>
				<para>If you choose not to enable automatic updates, properties of the target item that aren't recorded in the metadata will still be added. However, the imported information will never be updated by ArcGIS. For example, if the imported metadata describes the item as having one projection but its projection changes later, this change won't be recorded in the metadata when automatic updates occur. </para>
				<para>By default, metadata is updated automatically when you view it.</para>
				
			</bullet_item><bullet_item><para>If you import items using the ArcSDE administrative commands, the original item's metadata won't be imported. Import the original item's metadata into the new item with this tool.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>This tool can import one source item to one target item. To import one source item to many target items or to import different source items to different target items, open the tool in batch mode and set the tool's parameters appropriately.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para> Text or HTML files containing metadata can't be imported. </para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para> When using this tool in ModelBuilder, the Output Metadata parameter is derived from the Target Metadata parameter.</para>
			</bullet_item><bullet_item>
				<para>If you do not  have write access to the ArcGIS item or its metadata or the stand-alone metadata XML file that you are trying to modify, this tool will complete successfully but the item's original metadata will remain unchanged.</para>
				
			</bullet_item></usage><scriptExamples><scriptExample><title>Import the source data's metadata to an ArcGIS item</title><para>Imports the source data's FGDC metadata to a geodatabase item. The original metadata is converted to ArcGIS metadata. Some methods of importing data into a geodatabase handle the original item's metadata while others do not.</para>
				<code xml:space="preserve">import arcpy
from arcpy import env
env.workspace = "c:/data/data.gdb"
arcpy.ImportMetadata_conversion ("c:/data/streams.shp","FROM_FGDC","streams")
                    </code></scriptExample></scriptExamples></tool></metadata>