<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><Esri><MetaID SYNC="true" /><CreaDate SYNC="true" /><CreaTime SYNC="true" /><SyncOnce SYNC="true">TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate SYNC="true" /><ModTime SYNC="true" /></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle sync="true">Raster Calculator (Spatial Analyst)</resTitle><citRespParty><rpIndName /><rpOrgName>ESRI, Inc.</rpOrgName><rpPosName /><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint><city>Redlands</city><adminArea>California</adminArea><postCode>92373 - 8100</postCode><eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd><country>United States</country></cntAddress><cntPhone><voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum><faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum></cntPhone></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd>010</RoleCd></role></citRespParty></idCitation><idAbs>
			<para>Builds and executes a single Map Algebra expression using Python syntax in a calculator-like interface.</para>
		</idAbs><descKeys KeyTypCd="005"><keyTyp><keyTyp>005</keyTyp></keyTyp><keyword></keyword></descKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName sync="true">ArcToolBox Tool</formatName></distorFormat><distorTran><onLineSrc><linkage /><protocol /><onFunct><onFunctCd /></onFunct></onLineSrc></distorTran></distributor></distInfo><metainfo><metd Sync="TRUE" /></metainfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE" /><tool name="RasterCalculator" displayname="Raster Calculator (Spatial Analyst)" toolboxalias="sa" softwarerestriction="none"><summary>
			<para>Builds and executes a single Map Algebra expression using Python syntax in a calculator-like interface.</para>
		</summary><alink_name>RasterCalculator_sa</alink_name><toolIllust type="illustration" src="RasterCalculator_sa_h.png" alt="Raster Calculator tool dialog box" /><parameters><param sync="true" name="expression" displayname="Map Algebra expression" datatype="String" direction="Input" expression="expression" type="Required"><pythonReference><para>The Map Algebra expression you want to run.</para><para>The expression is composed by specifying the inputs, values, operators, and tools to use. You can type in the expression directly or use the  buttons and controls to help you create it.</para><bulletList><bullet_item>The Layers and variables list identifies the datasets available to use in the Map Algebra expression.</bullet_item><bullet_item>The buttons are used to enter numerical values and operators into the expression.  The  and  buttons can be used to apply parentheses to the expression.</bullet_item><bullet_item>A list of commonly used tools is provided for you.</bullet_item></bulletList></pythonReference><dialogReference><para>The Map Algebra expression you want to run.</para><para>The expression is composed by specifying the inputs, values, operators, and tools to use. You can type in the expression directly or use the  buttons and controls to help you create it.</para><bulletList><bullet_item>The Layers and variables list identifies the datasets available to use in the Map Algebra expression.</bullet_item><bullet_item>The buttons are used to enter numerical values and operators into the expression.  The ( and ) buttons can be used to apply parentheses to the expression.</bullet_item><bullet_item>A list of commonly used tools is provided for you.</bullet_item></bulletList><para>The Map Algebra expression you want to run.</para><para>The expression is composed by specifying the inputs, values, operators, and tools to use. You can type in the expression directly or use the  buttons and controls to help you create it.</para><bulletList><bullet_item>The Layers and variables list identifies the datasets available to use in the Map Algebra expression.</bullet_item><bullet_item>The buttons are used to enter numerical values and operators into the expression.  The  and  buttons can be used to apply parentheses to the expression.</bullet_item><bullet_item>A list of commonly used tools is provided for you.</bullet_item></bulletList></dialogReference></param><param sync="true" name="output_raster" displayname="Output raster" datatype="Raster Dataset" direction="Output" expression="output_raster" type="Required"><pythonReference><para>The output raster resulting from the Map Algebra expression.</para>
					</pythonReference><dialogReference><para>The output raster resulting from the Map Algebra expression.</para>
					</dialogReference></param></parameters><returnvalues></returnvalues><environments><environment name="Cell_size" label="Cell size">
						
					</environment><environment name="Current_workspace" label="Current workspace">
						
					</environment><environment name="Mask" label="Mask">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_coordinate_system" label="Output coordinate system">
						
					</environment><environment name="Output_extent" label="Output extent">
						
					</environment><environment name="Scratch_workspace" label="Scratch workspace">
						
					</environment><environment name="Snap_raster" label="Snap raster">
						
					</environment></environments><usage><bullet_item><para>The Raster Calculator tool is intended for use in the ArcGIS Desktop application only as a GP tool dialog box or in ModelBuilder. It is not  intended for use in scripting and is not available in the ArcPy Spatial Analyst module.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>The Raster Calculator tool allows you to create and execute a  expression that will  output a raster.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>Use the Layers and variables list to select the datasets and variables to use in the expression.  Numerical values and mathematical operators can be added to the expression by clicking the respective buttons in the tool dialog box.  A list of commonly used conditional and mathematical tools is provided, allowing you to easily add them to the expression.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>Full paths to data or data existing in the specified  current workspace environment setting can be entered in quotes (""). Numbers and scalars can be directly entered into an expression.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>The operators in the Raster Calculator tool dialog box are:</para><para>
						Spatial Analyst operators
						
							
							
							
								
									
									
									
									
								
							
								
									
										<para>/</para><para>()</para>
									
									
										<para>==</para><para> ()</para>
									<para>!=</para><para>()</para><para>&amp;</para><para>()</para>
								
								
									
										<para>*</para>
										<para>()</para>
									
										<para>&gt;</para><para>()</para>
									<para>&gt;=</para><para>()</para><para>|</para><para>()</para>
								
								
									
										<para>-</para>
										<para>()</para><para>()</para>
									
										<para>&lt;</para><para> ()</para>
									<para>&lt;=</para><para>()</para><para>^</para><para>()</para>
								
								
									
										<para>+</para>
										<para>()</para>
									
									<para>~</para><para>()</para>
								
							
						
					</para><para></para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>Multiple geoprocessing tools and operations can be created as a map algebra expression using standard python syntax.</para><para>If entering a complex expression manually using multiple tools,  make sure to check  the tool name syntax. Since python is case sensitive,  the expression will be invalid and fail to execute.</para><para>An example of the general format of a Map Algebra expression using operators is:</para><para> "inRas1" + "inRas2" + "inRas3"</para>
					<para>An example using several individual  tools is:Con(IsNull("streams"), 0, "streams")</para><para>Con(IsNull("streams"), 0, "streams")</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>The tool supports the standard Map Algebra syntax that is used in Python scripting.  The only differences are the following:<bulletList><bullet_item>You do  not need to put the output raster name or the = sign in the expression because the output name is specified in the Output raster parameter.</bullet_item><bullet_item>You do not need to cast input data as a  object when using operators.</bullet_item></bulletList></para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>You can easily clip a raster dataset by setting the extent environment  and specifying the input raster  name in the expression.  When the tool is executed, the resulting raster output will be clipped based on the specified extent.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>To create a raster with cells of a constant value, specify the appropriate extent and cell size environment settings and enter the numerical value into the expression.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>The performance of an operation may be enhanced by the deferred evaluation capabilities of Map Algebra. Deferred evaluation is an optimization technique where individual components of an expression are intelligently processed so as to minimize the creation of intermediate datasets on disk.</para><para>Only operators and tools that process on a per-cell basis can take advantage of this capability.    Operators and tools that support deferred evaluation are included on the raster calculator tool itself either as a button or in the list of tools provided.</para></bullet_item><bullet_item><para>Using the Raster Calculator tool in ModelBuilder.</para><bulletList><bullet_item>The syntax of the expression determines how variables are to be specified. If you select a variable from the variable list, it will be automatically added to the expression at the current cursor location. Upon model validation, <bulletList><bullet_item>Layer names will be  enclosed in double-quote symbols  (""). <para>Example: "inlayer"</para></bullet_item><bullet_item>Long, double, or Boolean-type variables will be enclosed in percent symbols (%%).  They do not need to be in quotes.<para>Example: %scale_factor%</para>
							</bullet_item><bullet_item>Variables representing dataset names or strings should be enclosed in both quotes and percent symbols ("%%").<para>For example, inraster when selected from the variable list will become "%inraster%" in the expression.</para></bullet_item></bulletList></bullet_item></bulletList><bulletList><bullet_item>In ModelBuilder, the following variable types are valid inputs for an expression:<bulletList><bullet_item>String</bullet_item><bullet_item>Boolean</bullet_item><bullet_item>Numeric: Double and Long</bullet_item><bullet_item>Data: Raster dataset, raster layer, raster band, .lyr layer file</bullet_item></bulletList></bullet_item></bulletList><bulletList><bullet_item>The Raster Calculator tool generally follows the standard connectivity behavior of models in ModelBuilder, with some exceptions resulting from the requirements of formulating a valid Map Algebra expression. These include the following:<bulletList><bullet_item>Variables are connected to the Raster Calculator tool when they are selected from the list of variables.  All variables are automatically listed in the Variable list inside the tool. </bullet_item><bullet_item>When a dataset or variable  is used in the expression, a link between the variable and the tool will be created. If you remove the variable from the expression, the associated link between the variable and the tool will also be removed.</bullet_item><bullet_item>If you delete the connection to a variable, the variable is not removed from the expression.</bullet_item><bullet_item>You should not  rename a variable that is connected to the tool, since the variable will not be renamed within the expression. If you do so, the expression will be invalid.</bullet_item></bulletList></bullet_item></bulletList></bullet_item></usage><scriptExamples></scriptExamples></tool></metadata>